Now that we know how to move around the file system, it's time for a guided tour of our
Linux system. Before we start however, we’re going to learn some more commands that
will be useful along the way:
● ls – List directory contents
● file – Determine file type
● less – View file contents
_____________________________

--------More fun with ls - Listing The Contents Of A Directory--------

-----ls ------

->  see directory contents and determine a variety of important file and directory attributes

	[me@linuxbox ~]$ ls
	Desktop Documents Music Pictures Public Templates Videos

-> Besides the current working directory, we can specify the directory to list, like so:
	me@linuxbox ~]$ ls /usr
	bin games kerberos libexec sbin src
	etc include lib local share tmp

~> Or even specify multiple directories. In this example we will list both the user's home directory (symbolized by the “~” character) and the /usr directory:

	[me@linuxbox ~]$ ls ~ /usr
	/home/me:
	Desktop Documents Music Pictures Public Templates Videos

	/usr:
	bin games kerberos libexec sbin src
	etc include lib local share tmp

-----ls -l ------
-> change to long format of the output to reveal more detail:

	[me@linuxbox ~]$ ls -l
	total 56
	drwxrwxr-x 2 me me 4096 2007-10-26 17:20 Desktop
	drwxrwxr-x 2 me me 4096 2007-10-26 17:20 Documents
	drwxrwxr-x 2 me me 4096 2007-10-26 17:20 Music
	drwxrwxr-x 2 me me 4096 2007-10-26 17:20 Pictures

------ls -t -------

“t” option to sort the result by the file's modification time:

	[me@linuxbox ~]$ ls -lt
	total 56
	drwxrwxr-x 2 me me 4096 2007-10-26 17:20 Desktop
	drwxrwxr-x 2 me me 4096 2007-10-26 16:20 Documents
	drwxrwxr-x 2 me me 4096 2007-10-26 15:20 Music
	drwxrwxr-x 2 me me 4096 2007-10-26 14:20 Pictures


~> Most commands use options consisting of a single character preceded by a dash "-", for example, “-l”,
 but many commands, including those from the GNU Project, also support long options, consisting of a word preceded by two dashes: "--"

We'll add the long option “--reverse” to reverse the order of the sort:
	[me@linuxbox ~]$ ls -lt --reverse

***Deeper look at ls ****
-rw-r--r-- 1 root root 3576296 2007-04-03 11:05 Experience ubuntu.ogg

1. -rw-r--r--  => Access rights to the file( Chapter 9 – Permissions): 
	+ The first character indicates the type of file
	=>> a leading dash "-" means a regular file
	=>> a “d” indicates a directory
	+ next three characters are the access rights for the file's owner
	+  next three are for members of the file's group
	+ the final three are for everyone else

2. 1  => File's number of hard links

3. First "root" =>  The username of the file's owner.

4. Second " root" => The name of the group which owns the file.

5. 32059 => Size of the file in bytes.

6. 2007-04-03 11:05 =>  Date and time of the file's last modification.

7. oo-cd-cover.odf => Name of the file.
___________________________________________________

----------------file: Determining A File's Type With file------------------------

~> the file command will print a brief description of the file's contents.
For example: 
	[me@linuxbox ~]$ file picture.jpg
	picture.jpg: JPEG image data, JFIF standard 1.01

**Linux is that “everything is a file

___________________________________________________

----------------less or more: Viewing File Contents With --------------------------------

~> Throughout a Linux system, many files are stored in text format and there are many Linux tools that work with text files. 
Even Windows recognizes the importance of this format. The well-known NOTEPAD.EXE program is an editor for plain ASCII text files

-> The "less" program was designed as an improved replacement of an earlier Unix program called "more"

+ less: allow the easy viewing of long text documents in a page by page manner. 
	-> less program allows paging both forward and backward and has many other features as well
+ more: could only page forward

Example:
	[root@nobody home]# more test.txt
	alaskjdflksj alskdjflksajd

	[root@nobody home]# less test.txt
	alaskjdflksj alskdjflksajd
	test.txt (END)

___________________________________________________

--------------------------------Symbolic Links + Hard link(more at Chapter 4)--------------------------------

	[root@nobody dev]# less /dev/
	brw-rw----.  1 root disk      1,   4 Jan  9 20:36 ram4
	brw-rw----.  1 root disk      1,   5 Jan  9 20:36 ram5
	...
	crw-rw-rw-.  1 root root      1,   8 Jan  9 20:36 random
	drwxr-xr-x.  2 root root          60 Jan  9 20:36 raw/
	lrwxrwxrwx.  1 root root           4 Jan  9 20:36 root -> dm-0
	lrwxrwxrwx.  1 root root           4 Jan  9 20:36 rtc -> rtc0

	lrwxrwxrwx 1 root root 11 2007-08-11 07:34 libc.so.6 -> libc-2.6.so

- most Unix-like systems it is possible to have a file referenced by multiple names

*Scenario: 
 + A program requires the use of a shared resource of some kind contained in a file named “foo,” but “foo” has frequent version changes. 
 + We include the version number in the filename so the administrator or other interested party could see what version of “foo” is installed. 
=> problem: If we change the name of the shared resource, we have to track down every program that might use it and change it to look for a new resource name every time a new version of the resource is installed.

=> How it solved: 
 + we install version 2.6 of “foo,” which has the filename “foo-2.6” and then create a symbolic link simply called “foo” that points to “foo-2.6.” => when a program opens the file “foo”, it is actually opening the file “foo-2.6”. 
 + The programs that rely on “foo” can find it and we can still see what actual version is installed. 
 + When upgrade to “foo-2.7,” we just add the file to our system, delete the symbolic link “foo” and create a new one that points to the new version. 

Not only does this solve the problem of the version upgrade, it also allows us to keep both versions on our machine.
 + O: “foo-2.7” has a bug (damn those developers!) and we need to revert to the old version: Again, we just delete the symbolic link pointing to the new version and create a new symbolic link pointing to the old version.

*Example explain:
	lrwxrwxrwx 1 root root 11 2007-08-11 07:34 libc.so.6 -> libc-2.6.so
=>> shows a symbolic link called “libc.so.6” that points to a shared library file called “libc-2.6.so.” This means that programs looking for “libc.so.6” will actually get the file “libc-2.6.so.”