The first thing we need to learn (besides just typing) is how to navigate the file system on
our Linux system:
● pwd - Print name of current working directory
● cd - Change directory
● ls - List directory contents
______________________________________________________

---------------Understanding The File System Tree---------------------

- Linux organizes its files in what is called a "hierarchical directory structure" => means: a tree-like pattern of directories (sometimes called folders in other systems)  
  =>> Like windows too
- 1 directory or folder: may contain files and other directories
=>> The first directory in the file system is called the "root directory". The root directory contains files and subdirectories and so on

-Linux always have a single file system tree, regardless of how many drives or storage devices are attached to the computer: /dev/sda1 ; /dev/sda2  =? all in 
  =>> Note that unlike Windows, which has a separate file system tree for each storage device: C:\ | D:\

- Linux always have a single file system tree, regardless of how
many drives or storage devices are attached to the computer. Storage devices are attached
(or more correctly, mounted) at various points on the tree according to the whims of the
system administrator, the person (or persons) responsible for the maintenance of the system.

______________________________________________________

-------pwd - The Current Working Directory-------

- At any given time, we are inside a single directory and we can see the files contained in the directory and the pathway to the directory above us (called
the parent directory) and any subdirectories below us.
  =>> The directory we are standing in is called the current working directory. 
Ex: [me@linuxbox Desktop]$ pwd
       /home/me/Desktop
=> user: me, hostname: linuxbox, folder on working: Desktop
_____________________________________________________

--------ls - Listing The Contents Of A Directory--------

To list the files and directories in the current working directory, we use the ls command.

[me@linuxbox ~]$ ls
Desktop Documents Music Pictures Public Templates Videos

=>Actually, we can use the ls command to list the contents of any directory,

- Filenames that begin with a "." character are hidden. 
=>>This only means that ls will not list them unless you say ls -a. 
____________________________________________________

-------cd: Changing The Current Working Directory --------

[me@linuxbox ~]$ cd /usr/bin
[me@linuxbox bin]$ pwd
/usr/bin
[me@linuxbox bin]$ ls
...Listing of many, many files ...

- These special notations are "." (dot) and ".." (dot dot).
   =>> The "." notation refers to the working directory 
           The ".." notation refers to the working directory's parent directory

Ex about ".."

[me@linuxbox bin]$ cd /usr
[me@linuxbox usr]$ pwd
/usr
Or, with a relative pathname:
[me@linuxbox bin]$ cd ..
[me@linuxbox usr]$ pwd
/usr

Ex about "."

[me@linuxbox usr]$ cd /usr/bin
[me@linuxbox bin]$ pwd
/usr/bin
Or, with a relative pathname:
[me@linuxbox usr]$ cd ./etc
[me@linuxbox bin]$ pwd
/usr/etc
[me@linuxbox usr]$ cd ./bin
[me@linuxbox bin]$ pwd
/usr/bin