At this point, we are ready for some real work! This chapter will introduce the following
commands:
● cp – Copy files and directories
● mv – Move/rename files and directories
● mkdir – Create directories
● rm – Remove files and directories
● ln – Create hard and symbolic links
These five commands are among the most frequently used Linux commands. They are
used for manipulating both files and directories.

__________________________________________________________

-----------------------------Why command-------------------------------

*BIG QUESTION: we can drag and drop a file from one directory to another, cut and paste files, delete files, etc. So why use these old command line programs?

The answer is "power and flexibility". While it is easy to perform simple file manipulations with a graphical file manager, complicated tasks can be easier with the command line
programs. 

For example: how could we copy all the HTML files from one directory to another, but only copy files that do not exist in the destination directory or are newer than
the versions in the destination directory? Pretty hard with a file manager. Pretty easy with the command line:
	cp -u *.html destination

__________________________________________________________

-----------------------------Wildcards-------------------------------

Since the shell uses filenames so much, it provides special characters to help you rapidly specify groups of filenames. 
These special characters are called wildcards. Using wildcards (which is also known as globbing) allows you to select filenames based on patterns of characters. 
- Usual using:
	* 	Matches any characters
	?	Matches any single character
          [characters]     Matches any character that is a member of the set characters
        [! characters]     Matches any character that is not a member of the set characters	
          [[: class:]] 	Matches any character that is a member of the specified class

__________________________________________________________
	
-----------------------------mkdir – Create Directories-------------------------------

The mkdir command is used to create directories. It works like this:

Example:
- Create a single directory named “dir1”
	mkdir dir1

- Create three directories named “dir1”, “dir2”, and “dir3”:
	mkdir dir1 dir2 dir3


-----------------------------cp – Copy Files And Directories-------------------------------

The cp command copies files or directories. It can be used two different ways:

	cp item1 item2  => copy the single file/directory “item1” to file/directory “item2”

	cp item1 item2 directory => copy multiple items (either files or directories) into a directory

Example:
- Copy the single file/directory “item1” to directory “item2”
	cp -r item1 directory (-r if item1 is folder)
- Copy multiple items (either files/directories) into a directory:
	cp item1 item2 item3 directory ( directory must exist)
- Copy the file with interative question: -i

- Only copy the file that dont exist:  -u


-----------------------------mv – Move And Rename Files-------------------------------

The mv command performs both file moving and file renaming, depending on how it is used

	mv item1 item2 => to move or rename file/directory “item1” to “item2”

	mv item1 item2 directory => to move one or more items from one directory to another.

Useful Options And Examples: mv shares many of the same options as cp:

	mv file1 file2 : Move file1 to file2. 
		If file2 exists, it is overwritten with the contents of file1. 
		If file2 does not exist, it is created. 
		In either case, file1 ceases to exist.
	
	mv -i file1 file2 : Same as above, 
		except that if file2 exists, the user is prompted before it is overwritten.
	
	mv file1 file2 dir1 : Move file1 and file2 into directory dir1. 
		dir1 must already exist.
	
	mv dir1 dir2 
		If directory dir2 does not exist, create directory dir2 
			and move the contents of directory dir1 into dir2 and delete directory dir1.
		If directory dir2 does exist, move directory dir1
			(and its contents) into directory dir2

-----------------------------rm – Remove Files And Directories-------------------------------

The rm command is used to remove (delete) files and directories:
	rm item1/dir item2

	rm file1 :Delete file1 silently.
	rm -i file1 :Same as above, except that the user is prompted for confirmation before the deletion is performed.
	rm -r file1 dir1 :Delete file1 and dir1 and its contents.
	rm -rf file1 dir1 :Same as above, except that if either file1 or dir1 do not exist, rm will continue silently

**Be Careful With rm!
Unix-like operating systems such as Linux do not have an undelete command.
Once you delete something with rm, it's gone. Linux assumes you're smart and
you know what you're doing.

** Useful tips: try ls with * wildcard before use rm with * wildcard

----------------------------------------ln – Create Links------------------------------------------
The ln command is used to create either hard or symbolic links. It is used in one of two ways:
	ln file link => create a hard link 
	ln -s item link => create a symbolic link where “item” is either a file/ a directory

1/Hard Link
Hard links are the original Unix way of creating links, compared to symbolic links(which are more modern)
**By default, every file has a single hard link that gives the file its name.
=> When we create a hard link, we create an additional directory entry for a file.
** Hard links have two important limitations:
+ A hard link cannot reference a file outside its own file system. This means a link
cannot reference a file that is not on the same disk partition as the link itself.
+ A hard link may not reference a directory.

**A hard link is indistinguishable from the file itself. 
Unlike a symbolic link, when you list a directory containing a hard link you will see no special indication of the link. 
When a hard link is deleted, the link is removed but the contents of the file itself continue to exist
(that is, its space is not deallocated) until all links to the file are deleted.
=>> It is important to be aware of hard links because you might encounter them from time to
time, but modern practice prefers symbolic links

2/Symbolic Links
=> Symbolic links were created to overcome the limitations of hard links. 
**Symbolic links work by creating a special type of file that contains a text pointer to the referenced file or directory. 
=>>In this regard, they operate in much the same way as a Windows shortcut though of course, they predate the Windows feature by many years ;-)

A file pointed to by a symbolic link, and the symbolic link itself are largely indistinguishable from one another. 

For example, if you write something to the symbolic link, the referenced file is written to. 
**However when you delete a symbolic link, only the link is deleted, not the file itself. 
**If the file is deleted before the symbolic link, the link will continue to exist, but will point to nothing. 
=>> In this case, the link is said to be broken. In many implementations, the ls command will display broken links in a distinguishing color, such as red, to reveal their presence.
